<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.kde.kigo.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Kigo</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Kigo</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kigo</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kigo</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kigo</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKigoxx</name>
  <summary>Go Board Game</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Joc de taula Go</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogo de Tabuleiro Go</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Stolová hra Go</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Гра у го на дошці</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxGo Board Gamexx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Kigo is an open-source implementation of the popular Go game.
      Go is a strategic board game for two players. It is also known as igo (Japanese),
      weiqi or wei ch'i (Chinese) or baduk (Korean). Go is noted for being rich in
      strategic complexity despite its simple rules. The game is played by two players
      who alternately place black and white stones (playing pieces, now usually made of
      glass or plastic) on the vacant intersections of a grid of 19x19 lines (9x9 or 13x13 for easier games).
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kigo és una implementació de codi obert del popular joc Go. El Go és un joc de taula d'estratègia per a dos jugadors. També es coneix com «igo» (japonès), «weiqi» o «wei ch'i» (xinès) o «baduk» (coreà). El Go destaca per la seva riquesa en la complexitat estratègica malgrat tenir regles senzilles. El joc es juga entre dos jugadors que alternativament situen pedres negres i blanques (peces de joc, ara fetes normalment de vidre o plàstic) a les interseccions lliures d'una quadrícula de 19x19 línies (9x9 o 13x13 per les partides més fàcils).</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kigo é uma implementação em código aberto do conhecido jogo Go. O Go é um jogo de tabuleiro estratégico para dois jogadores. Também é conhecido como 'igo' (Japonês), 'weiqi' ou 'wei ch'i' (Chinês) ou ainda 'baduk' (Coreano). O Go é conhecido por ser rico em complexidade estratégica, apesar das suas regras simples. O jogo é jogado por dois jogadores que colocam peças brancas e pretas de forma alternada (as peças de jogo são feitas normalmente em vidro ou plástico nos dias de hoje) nas intersecções livres de uma grelha de 19x19 linhas (9x9 ou 13x13 para os jogos mais simples).</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Kigo — реалізація популярної гри у го з відкритим кодом. Го — стратегічна гра на дошці для двох гравців. Ця гра має багато різних назв: іго (японською), вейдзі (китайською) та бадук (корейською). Го є стратегічно складною грою, хоча має доволі прості правила. У гру грають два гравці, які послідовно розташовують чорні та білі камені (ігрові фішки, які у сучасних варіантах гри виготовляють зі скла або пластику) на вільних перетинах сітки 19 на 19 ліній (або 9 на 9 чи 13 на 13 у простіших варіантах гри).</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKigo is an open-source implementation of the popular Go game. Go is a strategic board game for two players. It is also known as igo (Japanese), weiqi or wei ch'i (Chinese) or baduk (Korean). Go is noted for being rich in strategic complexity despite its simple rules. The game is played by two players who alternately place black and white stones (playing pieces, now usually made of glass or plastic) on the vacant intersections of a grid of 19x19 lines (9x9 or 13x13 for easier games).xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kigo</url>
  <url type="help">https://docs.kde.org/?application=kigo</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://kde.org/images/screenshots/kigo.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kigo</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
